<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
        <title>Jekyll Bootstrap</title>
        <description>Jekyll Bootstrap - Michael Ruane</description>
        <link>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog</link>
        <atom:link href="http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 20:39:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 20:39:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <ttl>60</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Use DVRPC’s Data Navigator for Municipal-Level Demographic Info</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;The Data Navigator allows visitors to find various datasets for a given municipality or county. It automatically provides a map of the geography being queried and a graph of the data. To date, you can view Census information, crash data, population and employment forecasts, and more.  New datasets will be added to this interface as they become available, so check back often. To view the application, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dvrpc.org/asp/DataNavigator/default.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.dvrpc.org/asp/DataNavigator/default.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/data_nav.png&quot; alt=&quot;data_nav.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/data-navigator.html</link>
                <guid>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/data-navigator</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DVRPC Counts Vehicle, Bicycle, Pedestrian Traffic</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;DVRPC collects traffic volume counts at over 5,000 locations each year, including vehicles, bicycles, and pedestrians. Vehicle and bicycle count data is collected by the pneumatic tubes you see laying across the road, and pedestrian counts utilize heat sensors that count passing people. In addition, there are 12 permanent bicycle and pedestrian counters on trails throughout the region. This traffic data is used by transportation engineers and planners, developers, and market analysts to make informed decisions in their work. To search by location or mode, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dvrpc.org/Traffic/&quot;&gt;access data here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/traffic_counts.png&quot; alt=&quot;traffic_counts.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/bike-ped-counts.html</link>
                <guid>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/bike-ped-counts</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>CyclePhilly App Data Available</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the CyclePhilly smartphone app has provided a valuable glimpse into the bicycling habits of Greater Philadelphia. Since it the app was launched, 220 bicyclists used CyclePhilly to record their routes, and the resulting data is now available for sharing and use. The data received provides an additional resource for local planners and agencies in an effort to understand bicycle trends, routes, and trip purposes, implement better bicycle facilities, and connect the region’s trail network, known as The Circuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three additional datasets have been added to the “download data” tab under “Tools and Data” on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dvrpc.org/webmaps/CyclePhilly/&quot;&gt;DVRPC web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/cycle_philly.png&quot; alt=&quot;cycle_philly.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/new%20data/cyclephilly-data-available.html</link>
                <guid>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/new%20data/cyclephilly-data-available</guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>CI2 Helps Planners Target Projects with Greatest Impact</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;DVRPC’s Community Investment Index maps the concentrations of recent (2000 through 2010) place-based investments that contribute to sustainable communities, as well as supportive planning activities and underlying development characteristics. Taken together, these maps summarize a location’s ability to leverage new sustainability- or livability-oriented investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of these maps is to help planning partners and project sponsors understand how new project proposals can support-and be supported by-prior investments across a range of disciplines (or “topic areas”). For example, a proposal for a new transit facility or trail connection could be strengthened if it builds upon a recent investment in affordable housing or a brownfield redevelopment proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dvrpc.org/ci2/&quot;&gt;Visit the interactive map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![ci2_image.png](/media/ci2_image.png) --&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/ci2.html</link>
                <guid>http://DVRPCFreight.github.io/Jekyll-Blog/products/ci2</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
